Ivan Starodubtsev Senior C/Linux Software Engineer

Personal info

Date of birth: November 13, 1986
Family status: married, 1 child



Executive Summary

- Linux software developer with strong user space development experience and basic kernel space development experience in C/C++ using all available GNU/Linux & UNIX tools.
- Overall experience in software development counts all years from **2010** till present.
- Experience in full software development process using different tools for version control, building the project code, code review, debug, tasks automation, tasks estimations etc.

Technical Skills	
Software Skills Category	Skill Sub Category
Functional Area	Software engineering and development primarily for embedded systems with/for Linux or other operating systems
Software Development Methodologies	Agile, Scrum, TDD
Programming Languages	C/C++(basic)/Java (basic)/Python (basic)/Lua (basic)/Bash/Sh
Operating Systems	Linux (host, target)/Windows (host)/VxWorks (target)/QNX (target)
Network	TCP/IP, UDP protocols
VCS	ClearCase, SVN, git (repo-git-gerrit-jenkins/branching model)
Development Tools	All available from GNU/Linux system environment (coreutils/binutils/gcc/gdb/make etc.) and other widely spread UNIX tools, custom and highly specialized scripting tools, MathCAD, MATLAB/Simulink, Coverity, Valgrind
Standardized Technologies	MPEG, DVB(-S/T/C), HDTV, POSIX
Specific Libraries	Cairo 2D graphics library, Skia 2D graphics library
Other software skills	Unit testing, Test cases development, Linux administration, DevOps (basics), Project infrastructure creation and maintaining using different tools
Additional Skills Category	Skill Sub Category
Academic skills	Mathematics (Higher and Calculus, Discrete, Statistical), Physics, Radioelectronics, Analogue and Digital Circuitry, Computer Science, Automation and Control Theory
Personal skills	Inquiring Mind, "Can-do" Attitude to Solving Tasks

Foreign language skills		
Skill Category	Spoken	Written
English	Upper-intermediate	Upper-intermediate

Education	
Entity:	KhAI (Kharkiv Aviation Institute), Kharkiv, Ukraine
Dates attended:	September 2004 - February 2010
Qualifications:	Master's Degree
Faculty:	Radio Technical Systems of Aircraft
Specialization area:	Electronics and Telecommunications

Phone: +38 067 92 62 642 | Skype ID: ivan.starodubtsev.skype | Email: ivan.starodubtsev.name@gmail.com | CV: CV.pdf

Professional Experience Summary

• Company: LLC "EchoStar Ukraine", Ukraine, Kharkiv, 63 Kolomens'ka str.

Duration: July 2013 - Present **Role:** Software Engineer

Project Description: Set-top boxes user applications, System applications

Responsibilities: Applications development, Build system development, Code review, Bugs/Issues fixing, Unit testing and test cases development, Project documentations

development, Project specific tools development, Profiling of applications

Technologies (common): C/C++, GNU/Linux, ARM, MIPS, GCC, GDB, Valgrind, Bootloaders, Command line interface, make build systems, shell scripting, Unit testing, Software security/encryption aspects, TCP/IP and UDP network protocols.

Technologies (proprietary): Broadcom SDK (Nexus)

Company: GlobalLogic, Ukraine, Lviv, 26 Sheptytskykh str.

Duration: December 2012 - June 2013

Role: Software Engineer

Project Description: Board support package (BSP)

Responsibilities: Device drivers development, Build system development, Code review, Bugs/Issues fixing, Project specific tools development, Project documentations development **Technologies (common):** C, VxWorks, ARM, GCC, Bootloaders, make build systems, shell

scripting

Technologies (proprietary): WindRiver workbench environment

Company: LLC "EchoStar Ukraine", Ukraine, Kharkiv, 63 Kolomens'ka str.

Duration: November 2011 - November 2012

Role: Software Engineer

Project Description: Set-top boxes automated test system applications, System applications **Responsibilities:** Applications development, Build system development, Code review,

Bugs/Issues fixing, Project documentations development

Technologies (common): C/C++, GNU/Linux, ARM, MIPS, GCC, GDB, Bootloaders, Command

line interface, make build systems, shell scripting **Technologies (proprietary):** Broadcom SDK (Nexus)

• Company: PJSC SRPA "Impulse", Ukraine, Luhansk region, Severodonetsk, Pobedy sg. 2

Duration: April 2010 - October 2011

Role: Software Engineer

Project Description: Instrumentation & control (I&C) systems for automation of large industrial facilities (nuclear/heat power plants, railway transportation automated management centers & systems)

Responsibilities: Instrumentation & control (I&C) systems software development, Project documentations development, Product functional testing

Technologies (common): C, ARM, Cortex-M3, STMicroelectronics STM32 MCUs, IAR Embedded Workbench for ARM, Device drivers development

Technologies (proprietary): I&C systems engineering technology in area of railway transportation